### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/utsavjain-1408 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Linux

Docker

Python

## Languages

Sanskrit

Hindi

Gujarati

**English** 

### Certifications

The Data Scientist's Toolbox
Being an Effective Team Member
Building RESTful Web APIs with
Node.js and Express

Python Data Structures: Stacks, Queues, and Deques

Big Data, Cloud Computing, & CDN Emerging Technologies

# **Utsav Jain**

DevOps Software Engineer @ Corning Inc., neé SpiderCloud Wireless

San Jose, California, United States

# Summary

I am a Software Engineer specializing in Cloud and Virtualization technologies.

My Professional goal is to be a Power Linux User and a pro-Python programmer.

My most proficient programming language is Python.

I am proficient in using Linux CLI and have done projects on AWS, GCP, and Azure using Linux cloud VMs. I have also containerized many of my projects using Docker and have used orchestration tools like Docker Compose for my projects.

I also have an interest in Data Science and have carried out some projects using Python (Jupyter Notebook). I have done various projects using supervised and unsupervised classification. I have used libraries like Panda, scikit-learn, numpy, etc for my Data Science projects.

Programming: Python, JavaScript, C/C++, Node.JS, LaTeX Web: Express with Node.JS, HTML5, CSS with Bootstrap, AngularJS, jQueryUI

Cloud: Docker, AWS, GCP, Docker Swarm, Docker Stack
Machine Learning: Jupyter NB, sci-kit-learn, Linear Reg, kNN, SVM,
DBSCAN, Dimensionality Reduction, PCA, SVD
Other Skills Proficient in Linux and KVM, GulpJs Task Runner, Kong
API gateway, VCS using Git

### Achievements:

- 1. Finalist in SILICON VALLEY INNOVATION CHALLENGE 2017
- 2. Fall 2018 Davidson Student Scholar

Email: utsavjain1408@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/utsavjain1408

www.utsavjain.info

# Experience

Corning Incorporated

4 years 7 months

DevOps Engineer

August 2019 - Present (3 years 9 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

Continuously improving security of cloud services.

Maintain CI/CD pipeline for cloud services.

Technologies: AWS, Python, Ansible, Terraform, Docker, Linux, Django,

MySQL, Jenkins, Bitbucket

DevOps and Build Release Software Engineering Intern

October 2018 - July 2019 (10 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

Part of the Engineering Services Team.

My tasks involve developing new and improving the existing python automation scripts and dealing with day to day operational issues.

I am also responsible for maintaining various software building tools including

Jenkins, SVN, BitBucket, Jira and rest of the in-house developed tools. Writing and maintaining the CI/CD processes using Jenkins, SVN and

Bitbucket

Technologies: Python, Linux, Django, MySQL, Jenkins, SVN, Bitbucket

## Education

San Jose State University

Master's degree, Computer Software Engineering · (2017 - 2019)

Gujarat Technical University

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Computer Engineering (2012 - 2016)